<record>
  <title>Huck Finn</title>
  <audio>huckfinn.mp3</audio>
  <text>
    <paragraph n = "1" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "1.2" start = "00.00" end = "07.93">You don't know about me without you have read a book by the name of The Adventures of Tom Sawyer; but that ain't no matter.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "1.3" start = "07.93" end = "12.25">That book was made by Mr. Mark Twain, and he told the truth, mainly.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "1.4" start = "12.25" end = "16.35">There was things which he stretched, but mainly he told the truth.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "1.5" start = "16.35" end = "17.84">That is nothing.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "1.6" start = "17.84" end = "24.56">I never seen anybody but lied one time or another, without it was Aunt Polly, or the widow, or maybe Mary.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "1.7" start = "24.56" end = "34.33">Aunt Polly--Tom's Aunt Polly, she is--and Mary, and the Widow Douglas is all told about in that book, which is mostly a true book, with some stretchers, as I said before.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "2" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "2.8" start = "34.33" end = "41.65">Now the way that the book winds up is this: Tom and me found the money that the robbers hid in the cave, and it made us rich.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.9" start = "41.65" end = "45.63">We got six thousand dollars apiece--all gold.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.10" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">It was an awful sight of money when it was piled up.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.11" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">Well, Judge Thatcher he took it and put it out at interest, and it fetched us a dollar a day apiece all the year round--more than a body could tell what to do with.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.12" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">The Widow Douglas she took me for her son, and allowed she would sivilize me; but it was rough living in the house all the time, considering how dismal regular and decent the widow was in all her ways; and so when I couldn't stand it no longer I lit out.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.13" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">I got into my old rags and my sugar-hogshead again, and was free and satisfied.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.14" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">But Tom Sawyer he hunted me up and said he was going to start a band of robbers, and I might join if I would go back to the widow and be respectable.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.15" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">So I went back.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "3" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "3.16" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">The widow she cried over me, and called me a poor lost lamb, and she called me a lot of other names, too, but she never meant no harm by it.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "3.17" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">She put me in them new clothes again, and I couldn't do nothing but sweat and sweat, and feel all cramped up.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "3.18" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">Well, then, the old thing commenced again. </sentence>
      <sentence n = "3.19" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">The widow rung a bell for supper, and you had to come to time.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "3.20" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">When you got to the table you couldn't go right to eating, but you had to wait for the widow to tuck down her head and grumble a little over the victuals, though there warn't really anything the matter with them,--that is, nothing only everything was cooked by itself.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "3.21" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">In a barrel of odds and ends it is different; things get mixed up, and the juice kind of swaps around, and the things go better.</sentence>
      </paragraph>

</text>
</record>
