<record>
  <title>war and peace</title>
  <audio>war_and_peace.ogg</audio>
  <text>
    <paragraph n = "1" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "1.2" start = "00.00" end = "01.60">CHAPTER II</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "2" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "2.3" start = "01.60" end = "05.75">Anna Pavlovna's drawing room was gradually filling.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.4" start = "05.75" end = "16.03">The highest Petersburg society was assembled there: people differing widely in age and character but alike in the social circle to which they belonged.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.5" start = "16.03" end = "26.60">Prince Vasili's daughter, the beautiful Helene, came to take her father to the ambassador's entertainment; she wore a ball dress and her badge as maid of honor.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.6" start = "26.60" end = "37.48">The youthful little Princess Bolkonskaya, known as la femme la plus seduisante de Petersbourg (the most fascinating woman in Petersburg), was also there.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.7" start = "37.48" end = "46.29">She had been married during the previous winter, and being pregnant did not go to any large gatherings, but only to small receptions.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.8" start = "46.29" end = "51.79">Prince Vasili's son, Hippolyte, had come with Mortemart, whom he introduced.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "2.9" start = "51.79" end = "54.96">The Abbe Morio and many others had also come.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "3" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "3.10" start = "54.96" end = "85.26">To each new arrival Anna Pavlovna said, "You have not yet seen my aunt," or "You do not know my aunt?" and very gravely conducted him or her to a little old lady, wearing large bows of ribbon in her cap, who had come sailing in from another room as soon as the guests began to arrive; and slowly turning her eyes from the visitor to her aunt, Anna Pavlovna mentioned each one's name and then left them.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "4" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "4.11" start = "85.26" end = "103.26">Each visitor performed the ceremony of greeting this old aunt whom not one of them knew, not one of them wanted to know, and not one of them cared about; Anna Pavlovna observed these greetings with mournful and solemn interest and silent approval.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "4.12" start = "103.26" end = "114.55">The aunt spoke to each of them in the same words, about their health and her own, and the health of Her Majesty, "who, thank God, was better today."</sentence>
      <sentence n = "4.13" start = "114.55" end = "127.70">And each visitor, though politeness prevented his showing impatience, left the old woman with a sense of relief at having performed a vexatious duty and did not return to her the whole evening.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "5" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "5.14" start = "127.70" end = "134.81">The young Princess Bolkonskaya had brought some work in a gold-embroidered velvet bag.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "5.15" start = "134.81" end = "149.75">Her pretty little upper lip, on which a delicate dark down was just perceptible, was too short for her teeth, but it lifted all the more sweetly, and was especially charming when she occasionally drew it down to meet the lower lip.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "5.16" start = "149.75" end = "163.63">As is always the case with a thoroughly attractive woman, her defect--the shortness of her upper lip and her half-open mouth--seemed to be her own special and peculiar form of beauty.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "5.17" start = "163.63" end = "173.06">Everyone brightened at the sight of this pretty young woman, so soon to become a mother, so full of life and health, and carrying her burden so lightly.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "5.18" start = "173.06" end = "186.28">Old men and dull dispirited young ones who looked at her, after being in her company and talking to her a little while, felt as if they too were becoming, like her, full of life and health.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "5.19" start = "186.28" end = "196.97">All who talked to her, and at each word saw her bright smile and the constant gleam of her white teeth, thought that they were in a specially amiable mood that day.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "6" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "6.20" start = "196.97" end = "217.08">The little princess went round the table with quick, short, swaying steps, her workbag on her arm, and gaily spreading out her dress sat down on a sofa near the silver samovar, as if all she was doing was a pleasure to herself and to all around her.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "6.21" start = "217.08" end = "223.84">"I have brought my work," said she in French, displaying her bag and addressing all present.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "6.22" start = "223.84" end = "229.75">"Mind, Annette, I hope you have not played a wicked trick on me," she added, turning to her hostess.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "6.23" start = "229.75" end = "235.45">"You wrote that it was to be quite a small reception, and just see how badly I am dressed."</sentence>
      <sentence n = "6.24" start = "235.45" end = "244.75">And she spread out her arms to show her short-waisted, lace-trimmed, dainty gray dress, girdled with a broad ribbon just below the breast.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "7" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "7.25" start = "244.75" end = "252.07">"Soyez tranquille, Lise, you will always be prettier than anyone else," replied Anna Pavlovna.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "8" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "8.26" start = "252.07" end = "__.__">"You know," said the princess in the same tone of voice and still in French, turning to a general, "my husband is deserting me? He is going to get himself killed.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "8.27" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">Tell me what this wretched war is for?" she added, addressing Prince Vasili, and without waiting for an answer she turned to speak to his daughter, the beautiful Helene.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "9" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "9.28" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">"What a delightful woman this little princess is!" said Prince Vasili to Anna Pavlovna.</sentence>
      </paragraph>
    <paragraph n = "10" language = "Russian">
      <sentence n = "10.29" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">One of the next arrivals was a stout, heavily built young man with close-cropped hair, spectacles, the light-colored breeches fashionable at that time, a very high ruffle, and a brown dress coat.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "10.30" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">This stout young man was an illegitimate son of Count Bezukhov, a well-known grandee of Catherine's time who now lay dying in Moscow.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "10.31" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">The young man had not yet entered either the military or civil service, as he had only just returned from abroad where he had been educated, and this was his first appearance in society.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "10.32" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">Anna Pavlovna greeted him with the nod she accorded to the lowest hierarchy in her drawing room.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "10.33" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">But in spite of this lowest-grade greeting, a look of anxiety and fear, as at the sight of something too large and unsuited to the place, came over her face when she saw Pierre enter.</sentence>
      <sentence n = "10.34" start = "__.__" end = "__.__">Though he was certainly rather bigger than the other men in the room, her anxiety could only have reference to the clever though shy, but observant and natural, expression which distinguished him from everyone else in that drawing room.</sentence>
      </paragraph>

</text>
</record>
